Okay, so here are two other tables in the zoo database.
حسنا، حتى هنا جدولين آخرين في قاعدة بيانات حديقة الحيوان.
The first one, taxonomy, gives the scientific names for
يختص الأول بالتصنيف، ويعطي الأسماء العلمية
all our animal species.
لجميع أنواع الحيوانات لدينا.
We've been using the common names like brown bear in our other tables.
نحرص دائمًا على استخدام الأسماء الشائعة مثل الدب البني في الجداول الأخرى لدينا.
This table gives not quite the full taxonomic name but a lot of it.
لا يوفر هذا الجدول اسم التصنيف الكامل إلى حد بعيد ولكن جزءًا كبيرًا منه.
The brown bear is genus Ursus.
الدب البري من جنس Ursus.
Species arctos.
أنواع الدب البني.
And the family Ursidae.
وعائلة الفصيلة الدبية.
And the oder Carnivora.
وآكلات اللحوم أودر.
We have to call this column t_order instead of order,
يجب أن نطلق على هذا العمود اسم t_order بدلًا من order،
because order is a reserved word in SQL for order buy.
لأن order كلمة محجوزة في SQL لطلب الشراء.
The t is for taxonomy.
يشير حرف t إلى التصنيف.
And if we look in this table over here, we'll see the common names for
وإذا نظرنا إلى هذا الجدول هنا، فسنرى الأسماء الشائعة
all of the orders.
لجميع الرتب.
Bats belong in the order Chiroptera and lizards and
تنتمي الخفافيش إلى رتبة الخفاشيات وتنتمي السحالي
snakes belong to the order Squamata.
والثعابين إلى رتب الحرشفيات.
and llamas and moose and warthogs all belong to the order Artiodactyla.
وينتمي اللاما والموظ والخنزير الوحشي الإفريقي إلى رتبة مزدوجات الأصابع.
Okay, okay, so
حسنًا، حسنًا،
really these tables are just here to give you more stuff to join.
فهذه الجداول توجد هنا لتمنحك المزيد من الأشياء التي يمكن إضافتها.
Big surprise.
مفاجأة كبيرة.
This time we want to find out which orders have the most individual animals
هذه المرة نريد أن نعرف أي الرتب بها العدد الأكبر من الحيوانات الفردية
in the zoo, and we want to give their common names like monotremes,
في حديقة الحيوان، ونريد أن نمنحها أسماءها الشائعة مثل وحيدات المسلك،
instead of their scientific names like monotremata.
بدلًا من أسماءها العلمية مثل مونوترماتا.
So you'll probably need to use both of those tables, the taxonomy and
لذلك سوف تحتاج على الأرجح إلى استخدام كلًا من تلك الجداول، التصنيف
the order names table, plus the animals table with the individual animals in it.
وجدول أسماء الرتب، بالإضافة إلى جدول الحيوانات مع الحيوانات الفردية داخله.
So the problem is, to list the taxonomic orders by their common names,
لذلك فإن المشكلة تكمن في إدراج رتب التصنيف وفقًا لأسماءها الشائعة،
sorted by how many individual animals we have of each order in the zoo.
مرتبة حسب عدد الحيوانات الفردية لدينا في كل رتبة في حديقة الحيوان.
To see the full schemas the tables, take a look at the instructor notes.
لرؤية المخططات كاملة للجداول، ألق نظرة على ملاحظات المعلم.